

Sigei kiplangat Isack

Born 25th of November 1995 kiplangatisack.is@gmail.com +254711398749

CERTIFICATES

Certified Systems Engineering Professional (CSEP)

Mar 2022

K.C.P.E

This is a certificate awarded to candidates after they are done with an eight year primary school programme. Mar 2011

K.C.S.E

This is a certificate awarded to a candidate once they are done with their four years secondary school education programme. Feb 2016

ASSOCIATIONS

LANGUAGES

English

Spoken: Fluent • Written: Fluent

INTRO

Objective Statement

To provide quality solutions to technical challenges and achieve organizational goals by applying

knowledge, engineering skills, and experience gained over time.

Personal Profile

I am a focused and dynamic engineering student who has a sound understanding of advanced engineering

techniques and exceptional engineering skills. Comfortable in fast-paced emergency room environments. A team player who is always ready to learn from others and share expertise, working

under minimal supervision.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Attachment

Unilever Tea Kenya L.T.D. (U.T.K.L.) • Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

Responsibilities

- * Assisted in Domestic Installation
- * Assisted in the Installation of Lightning Protection Systems (L.P.S.)
- * Motor maintenance, repair, and testing.
- * Earth resistance test and Earthing improvement.
- * Assisted is daily routine power line maintenance
- * Took part in panel installation of the valiant sortation project. Carried out cable laying, cable glanding, installation of trojan switches, and motor installation
- * Replacing transformer dropout switches
- * Dropping service cable
- * Installations of timers for security lights
- * Inspection and maintenance of the S.G.A. alarm systems

Technician

Evergreen Tea Factory Sotik (E.P.Z.) • Jul 2020 - Sep 2020

Responsibilities

- * Assisting in the installation of new machinery and commissioning
- * Timely inspection, testing, repair, maintenance, and service of factory machinery.
- * Proper record-keeping of all factory machinery and equipment.
- * Troubleshooting of default machines & equipment.
- * Daily maintenance of factory machines & equipment, installation of new machines
- * Electrical motor wiring and general wiring.

LAB TECHNICIAN

Rotik Mixed Day Secondary School • Jan 2015 - Jan 2016

Chemistry Lab technician

Physics, Chemistry and Maths Teacher

Form 2 class teacher



EDUCATION

Soft Morin

Software Engineering Moringa School • Jun 2022 – Present The intense learning and pressure of the Moringa school software Bootcamp has equipped me with immense knowledge in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Ruby, and Ruby on Rails. I'm extremely excited to continue exploring the tech world, growing/refining my toolkit, and contributing to meaningful projects!

Electrical and Electronic Engineering
The Technical University of Kenya • Jan 2016 – Nov 2021

Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical and Electronic (Control and instrumentation option). I did a project on the automation of water taps and hand sanitiser to prevent the spread of the Covid-19 Virus.

SKILLS

Web servers Web and mobile browsers React.js Ruby on rails

Database query languages (SQL, others) HTML

Github (or other software version management systems) JavaScript

Object oriented databases XML Algorithms CSS Bootstrap Programming

Electricity meters Electrical power generation Threephase network (electricity)

Troubleshooting Electronics Wiring diagrams Lightning protection Electrical installation

Electrical diagrams Direct current networks Electrical circuit technology (reading)

Digital circuits (electronic circuits) Engineering

Electrical circuit technology (design, drawing) Analogue circuits (electronic circuit)

Electrical assembly Alternating current networks Ducts and cabling

HOBBIES

Reading Science-based Novels
Watching Technology related Documentaries
Hiking
Swimming



LINKS

www.linkedin.com/in/ isack-kiplangat-46a756164



REFERENCES

Mr. Gordon Agutu • Lecturer Technical University of Kenya

Teacher • +254 727342682 • gordon.agutu@tukenya.ac.ke